Armenfilm studio production
Production by Armenfilm Studio
after Hamo Beknazarian
THE MEN
Screenplay by Edmond Keosayan
and Alexander Chervinkiy
Producer
Edmond Keosayan
Director of Photography
Nikolay Vasipkov
Production Designer
Rafael Babayan
Original Score by
Robert Amirkhanyan
Starring
Armen Dzhigarkhanyan as Ghazaryan
Mher Mkrtchyan as Souren
Azat Sherents as Vazgen
Avetik Geyorgyan as Aram
Armen Ayvazyan as Sako
Alla Tumanyan as Karine
Cast
L. Keosayan as Ghazaryan's wife
V. Podpomogov as the father of many daughters
S. Potikyan as the policeman
R. Kotanjyan as Levon
K. Khandanyan as Anoush
Arthur Sahakyan as Samvel
As you can guess,
if a movie is called "The Men"
then, the main character,
naturally, would be a woman.
However, let's not rush the story.
The movie is called "The Men",
and one cannot ignore that.
There are many men in Armenia,
today that is not a secret anymore.
We will tell you about
only four of them.
So, the first one is Vazgen.
Vazgen never confines himself
to merely his own interests.
Whatever dispute takes place in the city,
his is the last word,
because the wisdom and
the integrity of that man
is directly proportional to the respect
Vazgen has earned among all the strata
of the urban population.
"Let me think" Vazgen says.
You have to agree that is
surprisingly simple and wise.
And everybody around
suddenly feels at ease.
Sako.
He is not a painter.
But he understands life.
Clearly, the longing
for beauty inhabited
the most hidden corners of his
sophisticated soul for too long
and only now bursted out
with some violent force.
And if now sometimes Sako finds
himself walking on streets,
not very well-lit,
trust me, it's only so he can
once again realize how far
he is from all of that.
True, some, who encounters him,
are startled for a second.
But it's only for a second.
The entire city knows that
Sako has a will of steel.
Suren.
Suren jan.
With all due sympathy
to that man
one hardly can call him wise,
in fact, that would be impossible.
City folk might say that
he has air in his head,
and to a certain degree
that is a fair assessment.
This is a cake.
Not just a cake.
This cake is made in a factory,
which for many years
was run by Suren's
younger brother Romeo.
This is Romeo's wife Medea.
And this is their son Hamlet.
This is Souren's mom.
At first glance, everything
in her life seems ideal.
But that is not so.
The fact that Suren is still a bachelor
taints the taste of the cake
and the sound of the music.
This is Souren's grandfather Hamazasp.
They say, he was the first
to drive a car in our city.
They say, Souren's father Vardan
made it to Berlin with his lorry,
and on one of the front-line roads,
he picked up Marshal Baghramyan.
They say.
Grandma Vartanush knows very well
why Souren has air in his head.
In fact, he is the only one
who doesn't know.
The youngest of the four men,
who came to our city,
is a distance learning student
at the Agricultural Institute.
Aram.
Aram works in the third
taxi parking lot,
Where he has found connection,
true friendship,
and even protection
of the other three men.
Pay attention to that glance.
It is not innate,
it has been acquired
more or less recently.
The first overwhelming emotion
that befell Aram,
has made his glance that way.
Karine, the daughter of a respected
scientist Smbad Kalashyan,
did not have the faintest idea.
Of all the exemplary
qualities of a real man,
Aram possesses the most noble,
he is not talkative.
There existed too many incredible
situations in his imagination,
where he might have become
acquainted with Karine.
But none of them were
meant to arise.
This ancient dance
is called kochari.
It's main characteristic is that
only men dance it.
Women are occupied with housework.
So, men dance it
hands locked tightly,
huddled shoulder to shoulder.
Kochari will denote every
new chapter in our story.
He is called by the common
Armenian name Levon.
These are Levon's watches.
Not only they tell time, date,
the day of the week, month, and year,
but also the average
temperature on the Solaris,
and most importantly, the direction
and the speed of drifting icebergs.
Levon's job is difficult
and responsible.
The difficulty lies in that
he must always pretend
to derive immense pleasure from
the nauseating curiosity of tourists.
His job is responsible because
he has no right to forget,
not even for a minute,
that in front of him
is a distant West,
behind him
his native Armenia.
What else?
Oh yes, to our story Levon
has almost no connection,
which gives us the right
to return to our protagonists,
who today work for Intourist.
The road we drive now
is not on the group's route.
It's Vazgen's personal initiative.
He wise thoughts churned over
the unsolved problem
of his younger colleague.
Yes, this is the house
Karine lives in.
Here is some news.
Turns out, they know each other.
Sergeant Sahakyan, in fact,
as all traffic police in the city,
is not only an excellent professional,
but a well educated person.
Have you heard?
We are still going to have to deal
with Karine's little brother.
The dentist Ghazaryan himself
and his wife
don't have the faintest idea
about the wonderful
surprises awaiting them.
It seems,
that Vazgen's mind came up
with something of a salvation.
I feel like
he is about to pronounce
his famous "let me think,"
which means that everything
has been thought of already.
And there it is.
Turns out there is
a simple solution.
You need to do what Vazgen's father
did in his own time – propose.
Aram has no father.
But he has a mother.
She will go to Kalashyan.
It's like this, Smbat Arakelovich.
Here is my Aram, here is your Karine,
let's become in-laws.
With that in mind they went to
Ashtarak, the hometown of Aram.
This is Anoush, Aram's neighbor.
How quickly they grow,
the neighborhood girls.
Aram's mother.
This is grandma Nenek.
She is baking lavash.
Anoush's brother is called James.
As you can see, name trends
found their way to this place too.
Have you ever had a chance
to sit at a Caucasian table?
Not yet?
It means you are yet
to experience the awe
of your own merits, the ones
you didn't even suspect you had.
A true toastmaster will make sure
to point out the most hidden
and most beautiful parts
of your soul,
despite having just met you
for the first time.
And although glasses are full
with excellent grape wine,
a lot more will be spoken
than drunk at the table.
Maybe that is why there are
no detox centers in Armenia.
Who knows.
I feel like now Vazgen
will find the right moment,
to present to Aram's mother
the full importance
of the upcoming events.
Ануш, сядь рядом с Арамом.
Anoush, take a seat next to Aram.
Wait, what's happening?
Turns out the mother has
her own ideas on that matter.
You have to agree, Vazgen
couldn't have predicted that.
Ay-ay-yay!
But Vazgen couldn't abandon the idea
of his preconceived matchmaking,
since Aram didn't want to even hear
about anybody other than Karine.
For Vazgen there are no
impossible situations.
The uncle will ask for
Karine's hand for Aram.
Souren is appointed as the uncle.
Kalashyan.
Hello.
Are you Kalashyan?
Yes, but…
This is for you.
I don't understand.
Here are the photo documents.
I need to speak to you
one on one.
Come in, please.
Thank you.
I don't understand anything.
Comrade…
My name is Souren.
Souren can make a good impression
even on a professor,
although for him Russian is much
harder than his native tongue.
Pleased to meet you.
Oh, what a nice place
you have here!
Take a seat.
Thank you, you as well, please.
Oh yes, I told you,
here are the photo documents.
Look, here my nephew Aram
stands behind Vazgen.
I understand, that's Aram.
And here it says,
"For Karine from Aram."
I understand, it's from Aram.
Aram loves noone else like
he loves your daughter.
He is a humble man
of an average height.
Average?
How curious.
He studies at the Institute.
And who are his parents?
Villagers.
I think that...
You don't understand
today's village.
After all, what difference does it make
where his parents are from?
You should know that Aram is desparate!
One, two, three, four, five and bang!
The man is gone.
The guilt will torment you for life.
I won't go anywhere until
you give your blessing.
Nowhere.
True, he is my nephew.
But he grew up without a father.
I was a father, a brother,
an uncle, and a friend to him.
Well, it was a pleasure
to meet you.
Likewise.
Excuse me while I change.
Make yourself comfortable.
Such a nice man.
I apologize, dear Souren,
it took me a while.
Here, take a seat.
So many twins
under one roof.
Academia is academia!
To your health.
Thank you.
Help yourself.
I am helping myself.
Please.
Thank you.
Karine will be here soon.
That's good.
Very good.
My oldest daughter Desdemona.
Souren's surprise is so sincere,
that he switched to Armenian
without even noticing it.
This Karine is good too.
In Souren's opinion she may be
even better than the other.
If only Aram wasn't
so stubborn.
There is no option of giving up.
Ay-ay-yay!
Vazgen was so close
to abandoning this task.
But there was so much desperation
and hope in Aram's eyes.
And Aram understood that
Vazgen had a new idea.
It's a simple idea, isn't it?
So , let's get to the implementation.
Things are going
just as planned.
Get rid of the sign,
Aram, quick.
Come on, answer her,
say "Yes, I am free."
Aram!
Why are you silent, Aram?
This is unbelievable.
Ay-ay-yay!
It would be a mistake to assume
that our men never parted.
First of all, they parted ways
because of passengers,
who specified
very different routes.
Then, everybody had their own life.
All that is true.
But the friends never missed
a chance to be together.
And everytime they gathered
the pressing issue of
how to help Aram would arise.
Indeed, a great idea.
It cannot fail.
But even for his friend's sake, Sako
couldn't agree to play the hooligan's role.
All in all, it's understandable.
Souren is ready for anything, though.
That too is understandable.
Yes.
Unfortunately, Vazgen did not know
how to whistle.
Karine, unfortunately,
didn't get scared.
The kid did not cry.
It is hard for her to run.
It's hard for Vazgen to run too,
he has heart issues.
The elevated emotional state
of someone in love
wasn't considered by Vazgen either.
"Ognetsek" is "help" in Armenian.
Ay-ay-yay!
"Yes kez sirum em" is
"I love you" in Armenian.
Aram could not even dream anymore about
a wedding, or or any mutual feeling
or even getting to know her,
Only the possibility of seeing Karine
could brighten up his existence.
Seeing her?
Is not even that possible?
Let me think.
The following picture Vazgen
saw in his mind
was crystal clear.
Karine will definitely notice
this sad glance.
She will.
And when she notices it,
she'll definitely appreciate it.
But how to move Aram
into the dentist's apartment?
For Vazgen, of course, that wasn't
particularly difficult.
Vazgen's plan was simple
and could not fail.
No Armenian will fail to offer
hospitality to anybody,
who calls oneself a relative.
The wife will come home soon.
Maybe they are her relatives?
The wife came.
She tried hard to
recognize these relatives.
No.
She doesn't know them.
She doesn't remember.
No.
РаЗГОВОР не очень клеился,
а молчание СТаНОВИЛОСЬ ТЯГОСТНЫМ.
The conversation
and the awkward silence was becoming opressing.
All the best, young man.
Thanks for everything, uncle.
Thank you.
Do not be sad, brother.
Your uncle will take good care of you.
Farewell, auntie.
I am touched, very touched.
I will tell mom everything.
Till late at night, the couple
Looked through the family albums,
trying to find the missing link
in the endless chain of family members.
To no avail.
Why can't they dry the laundry
somewhere else?
It's wonderful I met you here, Souren.
Поздравь меня, друг, я женюсь.
Congratulate me, my friend,
I am getting married.
Don't ask me who she is,
where she's from, don't.
She is not a girl, she is a legend!
Vazgen! My dear Vazgen, come join us.
Don't ask who she is. Just don't.
My soul sings, let's sing together.
Sing quietly, no need to wake up the city.
Sako jan! Congratulate me,
I am getting married.
Don't ask who she is.
Now it's time to embrace yourself
for the saddest part in our story.
Do you remember Levon?
That guide who had almost
nothing to do with our story?
Of course, the next morning,
it snowed.
The old-timers couldn't remembersnow
that had fallen so early in the season.
Forecasters, as usual,
explained this rare phenomenon
with cyclones and anticyclones,
the collision of cold and warm air masses
somewhere over the Laptev Sea.
But you and I know why
it snowed today.
Aram, how are you?
Are you okay, Aram?
Today he could not
tell them the truth.
They have done
so much for him.
The end