http://subtitles.am
թարգմանեց նոչը։
Կինո Իբերիկա Միլիմետեր Ֆիլմ
Վրացական Կինո Կենտրոնի աջակցութեամբ
Տատո Ֆիլմ֊ի հետ համագործութեամբ
Նեմո Ֆիլմս, Բարանդոու Ստուդիոս
ԿՈՅՐ ԺԱՄԱԴՐՈՒԹԻՒՆՆԵՐ
Ինքն է։
Բայց նա մենակ է։
Ինքն է, ինքն է։
Լալի՞։ — Հա։
Ես Իւան եմ։
Հաճելի է։ — Իսկ նա Սանդրոն է։
Շատ ուրախ եմ։
Կներէք որ ուշացանք։
Մենք վերեւում էինք սպասում։ — Ոչինչ։
Ես նոր եկայ։
Ո՞ւր է Մական։
Մական չեկաւ։ — Ինչո՞ւ չեկաւ։
Չգիտեմ,
նա աւտոկայան չէր եկել։
Ես զանգեցի,
բայց նա չպատասխանեց։
Յետոյ հեռախօսս նստեց։
Չգիտէի ինչ անել,
ու որոշեցի գալ մենակ։
Կարո՞ղ է նա յաջորդ
աւտոբուսն է նստել։
Կարող ենք նրան սպասել։ Չգիտեմ։
Զանգիր իմ հեռախօսից։
Գուցէ պատասխանի։
Վստա՞հ ես որ նա է։
Նկարում որ ուղարկել էր,
ուրիշ սանրուածք ունէր։
Սրտովս չեն էս ինտերնետ ծանօթութիւնները։
ուրիշ տարբերա՞կներ ունես։
ունե՞ս թէ չէ։
Նա լաւ չէր զգում
եւ չկարողացաւ գալ։
Կարող ենք ուրիշ անգամ հանդիպել։
Ինչպէս ուզէք։
Չէ՞։ Ինչի՞ հետաձգենք
որ այսպէս ստացուեց։
Գնա՛նք։
Ես պէտք է լքեմ ձեզ։
Չե՞ս գալիս մեզ հետ։
Չէ, ինձ զանգեցին, գործեր ունեմ։
Պէտք է գնամ։
Բայց ես թողնում եմ քեզ
վստահելի ձեռքերում։
Կը գա՞ս երկու բառ փոխանակենք։
Բարեւ ձեզ։ Թամիլան դո՞ւք էք։ — Այո։
Ես Իւայի ընկերն եմ։
Նա երկու սենեակ է ամրագրել։
Բա Իւա՞ն ուր է։
Դուք պէտք է երկու ժամ առաջ գայիք։
Այո, ուշացել ենք։
Երկու համար այլեւս պէտք չէ։
Իւան չի կարող գալ։
Ինչի՞։
Չգիտեմ, չի կարող։
Բա երկրորդի համար ո՞վ է վճարելու։
Երեւի Իւան։ Նա կը զանգի։
Գիտէ՞ք որտեղ է համարը։ — Չէ։
Երրորդ հարկ, միջանցքի վերջում։
Մերսի։
Գնա՞նք։
Ուզո՞ւմ ես խմել։ — Չէ մերսի։
Գուցէ Մի՞րգ։ — Չէ մերսի։
Փոխե՞մ ալիքը։ — Ոնց հարմար է։
Գուցէ ջո՞ւր։
Լաւ։
Մերսի։
Մի քիչ է՞լ։ — Հա։
Գորի֊ում ի՞նչ գործի ես։
Բուժքոյր եմ։
Իսկ դո՞ւ։ Ես դասատու եմ։
Իսկ ազատ ժամանակ
կանա՞նց ես բերում հիւրանոց։
Չէ։
Իրականում առաջին անգամ եմ այստեղ։
Չէ հա՞։ — Այո։
Իսկ Իւա՞ն։ — Իւան ի՞նչ։
Նա այստեղ եղե՞լ է։
Չգիտեմ, երեւի թէ։
Վաղո՞ւց էք ծանօթ։ — Հա։
Մանկութիւնից։
Միասին ենք մեծացել։
Նախկին ֆուտբոլի՞ստ է։
Այո, լաւ խաղացող էր։
Ինքը նոյնիսկ խաղում էր
«Դինամո Թբիլիսի»֊ում։
Յետոյ թարգեց։
Համոզեցի դպրոցում աշխատի
որպէս մարզիչ։
Համաձայնեց երկար արձակուրդի համար։
Աշխատավարճը ցածր է
բայց արձակուրդը երկար։
Ու երեխաներն են նրան սիրում։
Ի՞նչ եղաւ։ — Ոչինչ։
Էլի ջուր կուզե՞ս։
Ի՞նչ ես անում։
Ի՞նչ է պատահել։
Կներես։
Ոչինչ։ — Կներես։
Նորմալ է։
Աւելի լա՞ւ ես։
Չեմ հաւատում։
Դէ ժպտա։
Այո։
Ի՞նչ պաստառներ։
Մեքենայի մէջ են։
Լաւ, ես կը բերեմ։ Լաւ։
Ուզո՞ւմ ես գնանք մարզադաշտ
ֆուտբոլ նայելու։
Ես չեմ սիրում ֆուտբոլ։
Սովորական ֆուտբոլ չի։
Կանացի ֆուտբոլ է։
Գորի֊ում աղջիկները ֆուտբոլ չեն խաղում։
Թբիլիսիյում խաղում են։
Մանանա, պաստառը տուր։
Ու զանգուլակը։
Կանգնիր կողքիս։
Մանանան լինելու է դիրիժոր։
Պաստառները լաւ են երեւում
եթէ դրանք միասին են բարձրանում։
Երբ մերոնք յարձակւում են
բարձրացնում ենք։
Իջեցնում ենք։
Երբ գոլ են խփում
թափ ենք տալիս։
Նորից փորձենք։
Մանանա, կհաւաքե՞ս պաստառները
խաղից յետոյ։ — Լաւ։
Հիանալի տեսք ունես։ — Մերսի։
Երբ դպրոցի տնօրէնը
աւարտի խօսքը, բարձրացրէք։
Ի՜ւա։ — Եկայ, եկայ։
Ինչպէս գիտէք,
Կանանց ֆուտբոլը
մեր երկրում նորոյթ է։
Մինչ վերջերս միայն տղամարդկանց խաղ էր։
Բայց ժամանակը փոխւում է։
Փոխւում է եւ կնոջ դերը
նաեւ հասարակութեան մէջ։
Մենք դառնում ենք աւելի ակտիւ
աւելի եռանդուն, ձգտող, աշխոյժ,
ուզում ենք աւելի շատ գոլեր խփել կեանքում։
Չեմ սիրում
երեխայիս մենակ թողնել։
Ի՞նչ տարիքի է։ — 13։
Տղա՞յ է թէ աղջիկ։ — Տղայ։
Իսկ ո՞ւր է հայրը։ — Գորիյում։
Ի՞նչ գործի է։
Ոչ մի։ Խմում է
յետոյ կռիւ անում։
Բաժանո՞ւած էք։
Արդէն երկու տարի է։
Անհնար է իր հետ ապրել։
Ամէն ինչ ջարդուփշուր է անում։
Ինձ էլ էր ծեծում։
Անցեալ անգամ
եկել էր ու սաղ աւիրել։
Ինքն իրեն կտրեց ապակով
ու շուրժը արիւնոտեց։
Որդուն վախեցրեց։
Գորիի աւտոբուսը մեկնում է։
Զբաղեցրէք տեղերը։
Կարող եմ յաջորդ ուրբաթ գալ։
Ուզո՞ւմ ես գամ։
Այո, իհարկէ։ — Աշխատո՞ւմ ես ուրբաթ օրը։
Մինչեւ երկուսը։
Ապա ես գա՞մ երեքին։
Մակային էլ կը բերեմ։
Հաւէս կը լինէր։
Խմա՞ծ է։
Կարծես թէ չէ։
Խմած չեմ։
Խմա՞ծ չես։ Ապրես։
Ո՞ւր էիր էդքան ժամանակ։ — Չի ուզում ասել։
Դպրոցում։
Աղջիկների թիմն էր խաղում։
Հանրաճանաչ լեհ
մարզիկ էր եկել։
Կի՞ն։ — Այո։
Սիրո՞ւն էր։
Չեմ սիրում
մկանոտ կին ֆուտբոլիստների։
Նոյնիսկ մի խօսէք դրանցից։
Մարինայի որդին լեհի հետ է ամուսնացել
ու պարզուեց որ նա լաւ կին է։
Ֆուտբոլի՞ստ է։
Չէ, բժիշկ է։
Բժիշկ կինը լաւ է։
Բայց նա կամուսնանա՞յ բժշկի հետ։
Մենակ չգիտես ուր թրեւ է գալիս։
Թրեւ չեմ գալիս։ — Գալիս ես, գալիս ես։
Այսօր, մարզադաշտում
կնոջ հետ եմ ծանօթացել։
Լեհի հե՞տ։
Չէ, Գորիից է։
Ինչի՞ Գորիից։ Թիֆլիսում քի՞չ կանայք կան։
Ի՞նչ կապ ունի որտեղից է։
Մեծ կապ ունի։
Դու էլ էիր գաւառից
երբ հայրիկին ամուսնացար։
Լա՞ւ չէր։ — Այո, լաւ չէր։
Ես պէտք է նրան ամէն ինչ սովորեցնէի։
Էդ ո՞վ էր ում սովորեցնում։
Ես քեզ՝ ինչպէս պահել սեղանի մօտ։
Ինչպէս պատառաքաղը բռնել։
Լաւ էլի։
Ի՞նչ էր այդ կինը մարզադաշտում կորցրել։
Եկել էր խաղը նայելու։
Հը՞։ — Խաղն էր նայում։
Ուզում ես ասել, նա յատուկ եկել է
Գորիից որ նայի
ոնց են աղջիկները ֆուտբոլ խաղո՞ւմ։
Գի՞ժ է։
Մենակ խաղի համար չէր եկել։
Բա էլ ինչի՞ համար։
Հանդիպում ունէր։
Գնա՞ց հետ։
Գնաց։ — Ուղեկցեցի՞ր։
Հա։ — Հետ գալո՞ւ է։
Տեսնենք, գուցէ։
Իսկ դու նրան կհանդիպե՞ս։
Երեւի։
Մենակ էդ գիտի՝
«գուցէ, երեւի,
տեսնենք»։
Մի բան արա, տղաս։
Մենք ծերանում ենք։
Նա էլ է ծերանում։ Արդէն 40 է։
Մեքենան կանգնեցրի՞ր։
Հա, խանութի մօտ։
Ոչ թէ աւտոտնա՞կ։
Աւտոտնակ վաղը կը տանեմ։
Վաղը մեզ կը տուգանեն։
Կրկին։ — Ես կը վճարեմ։
Դու երբեք չես վճարում։
Միշտ ես եմ վճարում։
Այս անգամ ես կը վճարեմ։ — Հա՞։
Աշխատավարձը կը ստանամ ու կը վճարեմ։
Ինչ֊որ երբեք չեմ տեսել աշխատավարձդ։
Ո՜վ կը մտածէր որ
40 տարեկանում դեռ ամուրի կը լինես։
Մամ, վերջացրու։
Երբ դու դառնաս հայր
կհասկանաս ինչի միջով եմ անցնում։
Կը լինի՞ հանգիստ ուտեմ։
Աւելացնե՞մ։ — Չէ, շնորհակալութիւն։
Օթար, օթար, գնա՛նք։
Ահա, հիմա նրան չես արթնացնի։
Օգնիր։
Օթար, վեր կաց։
Հազիւ քնել էի…
Տարա՞ր կայրան։
Այո։ — Ե՞ւ։
Ուզում է ուրբաթ գալ։
Ընկերուհու հե՞տ։ — Այո։
Հիանալի։ Միասին էլ կը զբօսնենք։
Ես չեմ գալու։
Գի՞ժ ես։
Քո համար է գալիս։
Երեւի սիրահարուել է։
Այդ պատճառով էլ չեմ գալու։
Կարծում ես, լա՞ւն ես իր համար։
Գնա՛նք Քոբուլեթի։
Յոգնել եմ Թիֆլիսից։
Ի՞նչ անենք Քոբուլեթիում։
Սիրուն է այնտեղ հիմա։
Թարմ օդ կը շնչենք։
Քեռուս մօտ կը մնանք։
Հայրիկ, կարո՞ղ եմ
հանգստեան օրերին մեքենան վերցնել։
Ո՞ւր ես ուզում գնալ։ — Քոբուլեթի։
Նոյեմբերին Քոբուլե՞թի։
Գի՞ժ ես։
Մարդաշատ չի, լաւ եղանակ է։
Գուցէ նոյնիսկ լողանք։
Կոկորդդ մրսում է
սառը մանդարիններից։
Եթէ լողաս,
Թոքերի բորբոքում կը ստանաս, հաստատ։
Մի խառնուիր իր կեանքի մէջ
Նա 40 տարեկան է։
Իսկ դու մի խառնուիր մեր զրոյցին։
Եթէ ուզում ես երբեւէ ամուսնանայ,
թող նրան հանգիստ, ինչքա՞ն կարելի է։
Անցեալ տարի վերցրին մեքենան,
Խմեցին, ու ջարդեցին այն։
Քեռի Օթար, այս անգամ չենք խմի։
Թարմ օդ կը շնչենք, մարմնամարզութեամբ կը զբաղուենք։
Ապա մենք էլ ձեզ հետ։
Մե՞նք ինչի։ — Մեզ էլ թարմ օդը
վնաս չէ։
Համ էլ կհետեւենք որ չխմեն
ու որեւէ տհաճ պատմութեան մէջ չընկնեն։
Ծովի հոտ է։
Ո՞նց ես։ — Լաւ, դո՞ւ։
Ի՜նչ գեղեցկուհի
ես դարձել։
Ո՞նց ես։ — Լաւ, դո՞ւք։
Բարեւ, քոյրիկ։ Ո՞նց ես։
Բարեւ, Աւտո։ — Աւտանդիլ, լա՞ւ ես։
Ո՞նց է ընտանիքը։ — Լաւ։
Սա իմ ընկերուհի Հատունան է։
Իմ եղբայր Սանդրոն։ Շատ հաճելի է։
Իր ընկերն է, Իւան։
Ինչ հաւէս ընկերուհի ունես։
Ինչո՞ւ էիր նրան թաքցնում։
Արդեն ֆլիրտում է։
Բարեւ ձեզ — Հաճելի է։
Կինս։ — Բարով եկաք։
Երեկոյեան կը տեսնուե՞նք։
Հա՞։ — Իհարկէ։
Մեզ մօտ հիւր կը գայ։
Լաւ, ցտեսութիւն։ — Մինչ երեկոյ։
We go to the beach, you come?
I expect a friend
may be later.
It also comes? - Yes.
What a great place to land!
Աննան չի՞։
Նա է։ Ի՞նչ է այստեղ անում։
Աննա՜
Մարզիչ Իւա, Սանդրո, ո՞նց էք։
Լաւ ենք։
Ի՞նչ ես այստեղ անում, բալիկ ջան։
Մայրիկն եկել է
աշխատանքի պատճառով։
Ո՞նց ես։ — Լաւ։
Մայրիկդ է՞լ է այստեղ։
Yes, I call it.
It makes me so happy to see you!
US too.
Can we join you?
Naturally.
Ո՞նց ես։ — Լաւ։
Շատ հաճելի է քեզ այստեղ տեսնել։
My best football mom does not leave me,
even during the holidays.
What are you doing here?
Ընկերուհիս այստեղ փակել է
գեղեցկութեան սրահ։
Ինձ գործիքներն է թողել։
and I'm here to recover them.
Դու գեղեցկութեան սրահո՞ւմ ես աշխատում։
Հա, ես վարսավիր եմ։
Anna, I throw the ball.
Խաղա՞նք։
Արի։
Anna throws the ball!
Let's play!
My mom and me against you two.
Anna, larger stones.
Here are our goals. - Here our own.
It seems a little small.
It will go.
Completed?
Where are you?
Both, mother and daughter.
And going on!
Goal!
Leave him.
I have to quit.
He scored.
It is good.
No compromise in sport.
That's what I taught them.
It's not badminton, but football.
What I taught you?
Did I learn anything?
Go! Anna!
Happening, I let you shoot.
Goal!
I can not stand it, I'm tired.
Congratulations.
You can not play better?
Let's eat.
We could take that
protect themselves from the rain? - Why not?
You can sit anywhere.
Thank you.
My sweet! Please, bring us
the tchatcha (Georgian vodka)!
So katchapuri and double lemonade.
Manana. - Yes?
After the game,
Have you recovered all panels?
Yes, that was difficult. - What for?
Two types would not make
without receiving my phone number.
And what have you done?
I gave them my number.
Had they known the jealousy of my husband,
they have not asked.
You are married?
Yes and no.
He is in prison. We have
a telephone appointment a week.
Yes, Father? - Where are you?
You are not ashamed?
We met friends
and we stayed together.
What friends? - Here, these girls
have already been waiting an hour.
We'll arrive soon. - Right now!
Hear them sing so.
Anna, come here, you will be soaked.
When you're leaving? - Tomorrow.
Pity.
We could have done
a stroll.
I'm on duty tomorrow
and I have to leave early.
I wish I could stay.
We could go fishing.
I'm never going fishing.
Long life to this place!
Bravo!
Honey!
We are going there?
Did you pay?
Bye.
A beautiful girl
waited for you for five hours
With his friends,
and she might have changed your life.
But you'd rather wander
and you get drunk.
We are not souls.
If you are.
So tell me
what you really want?
Is this any way to behave?
Look at me when I talk to you.
What kind of people are you?
Where did you grow up?
I'd really like to know.
What is your purpose in life?
Father, calm down.
What do you do with your life?
I really would like to know.
Otar, do not drink.
Did you say something?
You should not drink.
What did you say?
There tea. - We come.
The tea will not help us.
Hi, how are you?
Good and you? - Good.
How was the return? - Good and you?
I'm a bit tired.
You came back later?
Not really.
Did you bring the panels?
Yes I do . Where is Iva?
No idea. I wait.
Carry signs
in my class.
Okay.
Here's a few.
Much?
Have you class today? - Yes.
I disturb? - No.
The school is great.
What school did you go?
Evening classes.
The last year of school,
I did not go to class.
Why?
I was pregnant with Anna.
I often missed school.
I even had nightmares prof
put me on the board to punish me.
What are you doing here Mom?
I reported the panels.
Come home. - You are crazy?
Come home. - Anna!
I said, go home!
I hate these panels!
Why are you silent? Who is it?
The King Erekle.
Which? - Erekle II.
Erekle II was one
the most beloved of Georgian kings.
The people loved him.
He even gave him a nickname.
You remember? - Small Kakhi.
Just. Why small? - He was small.
In fact,
there is a popular poem about this king.
I'd like to recite it.
But I forgot it.
Could you refresh my memory?
Manana, I would
hear you tell me.
Our king is called Little Kakhi.
He took his armor
and cut in pieces with his bare hands.
Thank you.
May I ask you for help?
Who is it?
It is my great-grandfather Nikipore.
Do you know why his ear bandaged?
Once he ran into the forêtt
and a beautiful woman called him by name.
But he could not hear.
At night, they are seen at a party.
And she insulted
not to have heard.
Nikipore had warm blood,
he cut off the ear with a dagger.
He said she was useless
if he could not hear anything with it.
You would cut off the ear you
for a woman?
It depends on the woman.
And if I called you?
Call me. - Sandro! - What?
You did not have to hear me.
Okay, still calls me once.
Sandro!
See you tomorrow?
I can not.
My husband leaves prison.
He would stay there four years
but he released earlier.
He 36
and was already in prison twice.
The first time because he had
stung a friend with a fork.
He thought the guy
flirting with me.
How did you meet?
I was going to school. I was 14.
He saw me in the street
and I liked it.
I liked so many boys.
But once began Tengo
to accompany me home
and me gifts,
all other suitors are gone.
And I got pregnant.
Anna was 5 years old when he was imprisoned.
He stayed there four years and then went out.
This year, he returned it.
What happened this time?
He fought.
You love it?
I once loved.
Now I'm safer.
I'm tired of these problems.
He tries to change,
but did not succeed.
He also has bad luck, probably.
I do not know.
I'm going to talk to him.
I never am
felt better with someone.
Never.
All my life,
I went to the sea,
but I do remember the day
I spent with you.
I do not care who your husband
Moved with his fork.
If you want it,
we will get together.
I talk to him first.
But not now.
I need time.
I drive you to prison.
Okay.
I have to go now.
Sandro.
Please, as soon as I go down.
Would you katchapuri?
No thanks.
Okay, I'll take it anyway.
How much does it cost? - 80 tetri.
Thank you.
Is katchapuri good?
Not bad.
You see, give me money.
How much does it cost? - 80.
Take this.
Let's go to the bus stop.
We also see the bus
from here. Sit down.
The katchapuri is good.
It's for me?
He is handsome.
Do you like him? - Yes.
I asked the young in there
to do for you.
Thank you.
When my cellmate
saw it, he liked it so much
it also makes it and make a
requested me to go give it to his mother.
This time, I will do everything correctly.
Do you believe me or not?
But what does he do?
Who cares what he does.
What he's looking for here?
It is stuck to the outside.
I will help.
Where are you going?
Forget it, it'll make it right.
What's up with you?
I only want to help.
Leave him there will come itself.
It will not do. - We miss the bus.
Calm down, do not get excited.
I do not get angry, get back.
I told you
you should calm down.
To hell.
It is closed old man?
Yes, I left my keys inside.
Hold that.
And that too, please.
Hot katchapuri.
You buy hot katchapuri!
Katchapuri!
Good God.
Here you are.
Thank you. - You're welcome.
Are you in town? - Yes.
Can you take us
my wife and I?
Okay? - Okay.
Manana, go, come on.
What is there? - Nothing.
So kiss me.
What is wrong?
I did not miss You?
It makes me uncomfortable. - What for?
It's natural for someone
who just released from prison.
He's busy driving.
Relax.
Have you got a cigarette?
Thank you. And a lighter?
Thank you.
You make the taxi surcharge?
Occasionally.
I need a car today.
I will pay you and give
money for gasoline.
Where do you want to go?
You just get out.
Can not you not stay today?
I gotta get out, it's urgent.
What is there?
Why is this important?
That's a deal.
I want to know. - Relax.
So what do you say?
It is good.
Great.
I feel bad.
What is there? - I do not know,
I need fresh air.
Please, stop! - We are almost there.
I told you I felt bad
and I needed fresh air.
Stopped. - What is wrong?
I feel bad . I need air!
Thank you.
Good God.
Wait in the yard. I get on.
Throw the ball.
Ready?
Good job .
I have a wonderful girl!
You know how to catch, huh?
Do not let
you drag hands.
You make me fall.
No problem.
Natia!
How are you? - Good.
You're not cold?
Let's sit in the car.
There is the sun.
Come on then!
Hello. - Hello.
This is my friend Sandro.
Enchanted.
Sandro, could you leave us
alone, we need to talk.
How are you? - I'm fine.
You're in what month? - At the third.
Does your family know?
Yes I do.
Do they know it's me? - No.
My wife does she know anything?
No. - Really? - No.
Natia, listen to me.
I hate to talk about it,
but you have to understand me.
I can not take
all the baby's responsibility.
I'll help, of course.
I can not do much,
I just got out of prison.
I have no work, no perspective.
Everything is upside down.
What should I say,
I hate abortions.
But have we
alternatively?
I do not avorterai.
I do not want it.
I can understand, but
There he has another alternative?
I do not know, but
I do not avorterai.
The money I make it my business.
I'll bring you the best doctor.
You get out unharmed, do not worry.
I do not want your money. - Stopped.
Okay, you did not need money.
Okay, you do not want an abortion.
Me neither, I hate that, but
this is the only possibility.
Otherwise, you propose what else?
I do not do it.
Listen to me Natia.
Come to this address.
My condolences.
My sincere condolences.
Are you the mother of Zaza? - Yes.
I am a friend of Zaza.
I come directly from prison.
He do this for you
and requested me to bring it to you.
How nice! Thank you very much!
Nuzgar calls.
How is my son? - Uncle Nuzgar!
Uncle Nuzgar, Natela calling you.
Thank you, you have made me
so happy.
See the care of my son.
What is going on? - Zaza sent me
a ring from prison.
This man is his friend.
Hello.
You were in prison with Zaza? - Yes.
When did you get out? - Today.
Congratulations. - Thank you.
Hello.
You have a momentt
to talk about Zaza?
It's certain. - Please, come.
What is it, Nuzgar?
He was in prison with Zaza
and it came out today.
Come in.
I'll be right back.
Girls, leave us alone for a while.
Have you phoned
for meat? - It makes the Soso.
So how are you?
I just got out.
I take my freedom.
Nuzgar, look at these beautiful fish.
Which specimen.
This is what we serve
during the vigil.
Viewing see.
It's fresh.
He made me a special price.
How many? - First, he said 20 Lari.
But we agreed to 18.
Like a catfish,
we will receive tomorrow
fresh from the Alasani.
Fish is good. - Good, but expensive.
We need
at least 20kg, is not it? - Yes.
You will not find cheaper.
We'll talk later.
Seller of fish
awaits our response.
It will sell
perhaps someone else.
That seems still expensive.
Nothing but fish costs 400.
With catfish ...
this is 800. - Here we go.
What are we doing?
Maybe should I buy carp.
Excuse me if I interfere,
These are not my things.
I think that would be enough
with only one kind of fish.
Why?
Zaza needs money in prison.
Zaza needs money? Why?
He lost cards.
He must pay today.
Zaza has played and lost?
He is a believer, it is not possible
he played.
He often visits the priest.
I know but he still played.
I must visit him in prison.
He has not played for ages.
How would this be this possible?
Calm down, give him a visit.
That's what I say.
I know you're short of money.
Two types of fish are useless.
A sufficient.
In addition, we could
reflect on other points.
It's a tricky thing.
I saw the coffin at the entrance.
And? - It is an expensive coffin.
Maybe we pourraitt
exchange it against cheaper.
What the hell are you talking about ?!
We think about something else.
Where stands the funeral meal?
In a restaurant.
How much is it per person?
20 Lari. - 20 Lari?
And we make our wine.
20 Lari with your own wine?
It's way too much.
How many people are invited?
250 - 250?
We can prepare a table in the courtyard?
You have a yard, is not it?
Yes I do. - Once on the other side.
Look to see.
We go up a tent in the courtyard.
Who still uses a tent today?
Why not?
The weather is nice. There is plenty of room.
We provide wooden tables and benches.
Overlaid with paper.
Lari 400 should suffice.
I work benches. - And or?
250 guests 20 times Lari
per person, this is 5000.
In the court it would cost 500.
You would save a lot with that.
You would help Zara
and in addition there would money.
Do not tell us what to do.
We do this by themselves.
Listen, brother.
I do not tell you anything.
I am here to help.
If you do not need it, I'm going.
Okay, do not upset you,
he only give its opinion.
Yes, but it was moved.
Your son sent me here.
Our family is in penury!
I can see that, but do you believe
I can see mine pink?
I get out of prison.
Here's my discharge papers.
I have better things to do
than discussing funeral meal.
I'm only here to help Zaza.
It's for you to decide.
Let us help your son.
The priest arrived
for the funeral ceremony.
I arrive in a minute.
Okay, I'm going.
Should I come back in an hour?
Okay.
I scrape the bottom of the barrel
Zaza, but without warranty.
See you later.
Oh my God.
My apologies.
I am sorry.
Let's stay a little.
Thank you.
How are you?
Why do not you greet Sandro?
Hello.
We have 30 minutes.
Make us beautiful.
No thanks. - Come here.
It's the best hairdresser in town.
Sit down.
You do not have much to do
with her hair.
Would you wash your hair?
No. - Of course, he would.
You changed the store, is not it?
No.
These photos
were already there? - Yes.
Are you sure? - Yes.
That's fine then.
Do not smoke here. Go to the back.
Hi, Natia.
How are you?
I am happy to see you.
I have good news.
In an hour
I have 2000 lari for you.
I'm serious.
I do not force you to abort.
You must also understand my situation.
I go to jail.
But I have already 2000 lari for you.
We'll take care of the rest later.
Where is the problem?
Calm down only, okay?
Manana, where is the ashtray?
Yet it was here somewhere.
What are you doing here?
Here is your pay for the week.
Do not come back.
Now outside.
What are you doing?
Get out of here.
What is there? What happened?
You caress my housekeeper
in my presence!
You are crazy?
for several hours.
What do you want?
Do you still have your whole head?
Nothing happened.
Look at me!
Nothing happened. Including?
Tengo, I beg you, go away! - What for?
Outside! - I swear. Listen to me.
Come here! - Leave me out!
Do not touch me!
Calm down. - Outside!
Do not touch me! - Calm down.
I told you, do not touch me!
You will catch the iron
on the head.
You are crazy? Go, go.
Behave. We are not alone.
How can you be jealous
Natia as a refugee?
Are you really mad or what?
Tengo, leave me alone.
Relax so.
Let go of my hand.
I détendrai when you're gone.
Are you sure? - Yes.
Sure? - Yes.
Do not hit me!
Then draws up!
You act
like a fool. - Outside!
You got a grain.
Demented.
No need to sit you.
I do not you will cut off their hair.
Are you married, Sandro?
No.
If you want my advice, do not get married.
Why?
I ended up in jail
because of my wife.
I do not know
what to do with this Natia.
She is pregnant
and does not want an abortion.
What can I do?
What happens with Zaza?
He played with Rezo and lost.
You remember Rezo?
Yes I do. But Rezo has a phone,
why he did not call himself?
There are more.
They found
put him four more years.
For possession of phone
and for games.
Why did they let you out?
You know I'll finish
to know the truth.
Listen, Nodar.
The prison administration knew everything.
That Rezo had a laptop and played.
It forced people,
to call their families
to ask for money.
The guards came and ditt
than those
does not denounce the players,
take two more years.
All were afraid of Rezo
and held their tongue,
but I was tired.
If you got tired of Rezo,
why you're worried about his money?
In addition, Zaza stopped playing.
He became a believer.
There I really need money.
And that's how you gonna have?
You know I will refund
soon as I can. You know me.
I'll go talk to them
You and you disappear.
Right now.
Bastard! - Do not touch me!
Do not touch me!
Hey you! Let him go,
it is the driver.
Go to your self. - Let me pass.
I told you to go to the car.
Leave him!
I'll kill the bastard!
So grab one!
Leave me! - Standing!
Get your hands!
Spread the legs!
It has nothing to do with it.
Let it go!
I'm his father.
Let me explain.
Wait a minute. - It is his father.
Let him explain.
He was freed
Prison today.
He came to the funeral and said
my son had gambling debts.
Do it quiet, I hear nothing.
Checks his papers.
He said that my son
Lari 2000 would have lost the game.
He said I had to give him the money.
It was released today.
Put him in the car, I will see that.
My stepfather died,
his grandfather.
Please, remove the handcuffs.
If his mother will
a heart attack.
His father died, his eldest son
in prison and he with handcuffs.
Leave me.
Nodar, you're a hero.
You saved us. - Thank you.
I will not forget.
Nodar, thanks. - You're welcome.
We will always be your debtors.
Why do you need money?
For the family?
Yes I do.
I have money.
I bring to your family.
Give it to the guy,
who came with me.
Here, take this.
Ciao.
Sandro.
Bring this to Natia,
she lives among refugees.
And take what I owe you.
I do not want any money.
Thank you.
Hi guys. - Hello.
Do you know where lives Natia?
Natia how?
The slim girl
who works at the beauty salon.
What do you want him?
I have something to give. - What?
And who are you? - His brother.
What do you give him?
Money.
Follow me.
Gela, all right? - Yes, I am fine.
Here is my father.
Dad, here. .. - Sandro.
Irodi, sit down.
Natia here? - Natia faitt
shopping, she will be back soon.
Sit down, Sandro.
Dad, then rest and listen.
What is it, son?
Dad, this is the father of the child Natia.
I hardly know her.
I saw her only twice
ten minutes.
Twice ten minutes, huh?
And you came
to get her pregnant?
Would you insinuate
my sister is a whore?
We are family, understand?
So think before you speak.
Calm down, son.
You put pregnant
in ten minutes?
Gela, what is it?
Tell her you're not
pregnant with me.
Gela, what do you want from him?
He must take
responsibility for his actions.
What are you talking about?
I hardly know.
So what is he doing here?
How do you want me to know?
Did you say that
Tengo's friend hath made pregnant.
The did you say or not? - Yes, but.. .
The did you or did you not say? - Yes.
So here it is.
If it's not him,
what is he doing here?
Have you ever seen Tengo friends to come here?
And bring money?
What is that?
That's all you offer?
We the refugees, we
are not worth more than that?
You sleep with our wives
I'll put you to pieces!
Go on, do it!
Wait. Stopped.
Aunt, I beg you, help me!
What is happening here?
Stand still for a moment.
Wait, I'll explain.
Tell me all. - I will tell you.
She is pregnant.
What are you saying?
He got her pregnant.
And he does not want to marry her.
Is she pregnant by him?
Yes I do.
It's true what I hear?
You are not ashamed?
You refuse to be the father?
Wait, do not interrupt me.
Then you have no shame?
You repudiated your own child?
How can you push
your child and this angel?
So keep quiet!
How can you push them?
Answer me.
You should be ashamed.
Future father,
a respectable man.
A true Georgian.
A true Georgian
does not behave well.
You should move mountains
for your child.
It is here, under your nose,
and you do not want?
Look me in the eyes!
We trust you Sandro.
Pay attention to them.
Have my blessing, my children!
God bless you.
Do not turn off your mobile, Natia.
Gela, everything is in order?
Yes everything is fine.
Why are they holding hands?
The girls walk like that.
Hello. - Hello.
How are you, Lali? - Well, here Maka.
I will. - Hold me the hand.
Enchanted.
The road was good? - Yes.
And how are you? - Not bad.
Let's go? Our car is outside.
Maka Come, sit here.
Sit Lali.
It does not open.
It's closed? - Most likely.
Sit down.
Hello, I called the 408.
The balcony door did not open.
Why I want to open it?
I want to be open, that's all.
You tell me
that you're doomed?
Listen, I pay the room
because of the balcony and the view.
I do not care,
I want the view.
I need the view.
Well, find Tamila
and send someone.
I want the view!
Idiots!
They say it's cold
and they condemned the balcony.
Never mind anyway, I can not
not enjoy the view.
Describe me just what you see.
Thus, it is more interesting.
What I see here?
I see the Old Town of Tbilisi.
The city with many balconies.
The Mtkvari River.
It also runs in Gori, right? - Yes.
Here it is different.
She has more meandering.
Barataschwili liked to walk here.
Alone? - Alone.
I can see
Cathedral of the Trinity.
You describe well.
Come and sit next to me.
I can not stay.
Can you take a walk with me?
I'll take you to the station
if you want. I am sorry.
Maka, I'm going.
I'm waiting at the station.
Iva, thou escorted?
Of course.
I take the bus at 7:00.
If you do not catch it, call me.
We then see in Gori.
Ciao.
Would you like something to drink? - No.
A fruit. We have apples.
Yes, I would like one.
Do I peel?
No, I'll do it myself.
Really? - Yes.
I need the room.
Azerbaijanis are coming soon.
They will eat the Chinkali to the balcony.
I give you another room.
No thanks. - Okay.
The balcony door is doomed.
We open.
They disaientt
we must give room.
I heard it.
Let's go? - Soon.
Hello.
Let's hear some noise of the city,
then go.
We Dance?
But we have no music.
It does not matter.
You From?
Or? - A Kobuleti.
My mother asked me
go take it.
Why did you need me for that?
To keep you awake on the road?
Yes I do.
I had a bad dream.
I trained a team
Blind footballers.
I was severe.
What do you have?
Are you still depressed?
Looks good.
Something happened?
Nothing important. - Tell me.
A friend of mine was imprisoned.
Her friend is pregnant.
Which friend?
I am your friend.
I still have another one.
We studied together.
It will probably be for five years.
Her friend made me sad.
She is pregnant and does not know where to go.
I took it with me.
There is a woman with you?
Yes I do.
And she will stay five years with you
until the guy so?
Why do not you marry it?
She looks ready for that.
I must tell you something.
What is it?
We have a guest.
A woman - a friend of mine.
She will stay with us a while.
Who is she?
Only a friend.
You could also
up to something else.
What do you mean?
It is just a friend.
A friend lives in you
in our presence - for a moment.
I've never heard
talk about what kind of friendship.
You know her?
No.
Who are his parents?
It is not Tbilisi.
I'm fed up
thy rustic.
Besides a man intelligentt
should marry a girl from the province.
Including?
Why marry?
I will not marry her.
So keep it to yourself.
How old?
Around 25 years.
How are you? You're bored? - No.
Mother, Natia here.
Enchanted, I'm Lia.
You can call me Aunt Lia.
And here Otar. - Hi, delighted.
Hello. - Hello. - Here Iva.
Prepare dinner for tonight.
I brought all kinds of treats.
But you have to go shopping.
I am helping you.
No thank you, go watch TV.
Assistance is not required.
Lia takes care of everything.
Mother what should I buy?
Bread, tea, peas.
Sandro brings glasses for that.
Where did you get that?
Your uncle gave them to me.
Would you like to watch
football or I change the channel?
Let only.
Do you like football? - Yes.
This is part of the German championship,
but I do not recognize the teams.
Hamburg and Dortmund.
Well.
You love German football?
No, Italian.
Girls love Italian football.
Beautiful kids in shorts,
running after a ball.
It's not that.
I just love their style.
I like the importance given
defense.
And what do you like it?
They always play defense.
Their goals are always in danger.
It is tense,
when you see them play.
I love this tension.
But it's not just the tension.
They also score goals, is not it?
Oh yes, they do.
Past! Make a pass! He did what there?
That is why I
do not like the German football.
What could he do? - He should have
play the ball from the right.
The right or left? - The right.
You, you understand what football.
Come over here.
Look at him.
This boy has problems.
Then go talk to him.
what should I tell him?
Does it really
defrauded a family in mourning?
He has not cheated.
The son of the family
lost cards.
Without your man
the type is now in penury.
There would be problems in prison.
He behaved bravely.
He was attacked by 20 men,
but he was not afraid and remained calm.
You're a good man.
And you will find a good woman.
Bring her here too.
For hairdressing.
I cap both men
than women.
Unisex.
Sandro: ANDRO SACHVARELISDE
Manana: IA SUCHITASCHWILI
Iva: ARTSCHIL KIKODSE
Tengo: VAKO TSCHATSCHANISDE
Sandros father KACHI KAWASADSE
Sandros mother MARINA KARZIWADSE
Lali: MARIKA ANTADSE
Natia: SOPHO GWRITISCHWILI
Natias Bruder: JANO ISORIA
Zazas Vater: MARLEN EGUTIA
Nodar: Lewan Ghlonti
Directed Lewan KOGUASCHWILI
Scenario: BORIS Frumin,
Lewan KOGUASCHWILI
Production: Suliko ZULUKIDSE,
Lewan KOGUASCHWILI, OLENA JERSCHOWA
Image: TATO KOTETISCHWILI
Sets: KOTE JAPARIDSE
Costumes Tinatin KWINIKADSE
Mounting: NODAR NOSADSE
Executive Producer: KETI MATSCHAWARIANI
French Adaptation: Martial Knaebel